Hey! Come here!
I'm on my way.
Are you here to kill me?
I know what this is.
I've seen one before.
Many, many years ago.
It belonged to a man I met
in a half-remembered dream.
A man possessed of some radical notions.
What is the most resilient parasite?
A bacteria? A virus?
An intestinal worm?
What Mr. Cobb is trying to say
An idea.
Resilient. Highly contagious.
Once an idea has taken hold of the brain,
it's almost impossible to eradicate.
An idea that is fully formed, fully understood,
that sticks.
Right in there somewhere.
For someone like you to steal?
Yes. In the dream state, your conscious defenses are lowered...
and that makes your thoughts vulnerable to theft.
It's called extraction.
Mr. Saito, we can train your subconscious to defend itself...
from even the most skilled extractor.
How can you do that?
Because I am the most skilled extractor.
I know how to search your mind and find your secrets.
I know the tricks.
And I can teach them to you, so that even when you're asleep...
your defense is never down.
Look, if you want my help,
you're gonna have to be completely open with me.
I need to know my way around your thoughts better than your wife...
better than your therapist, better than anyone.
If this is a dream, and you have a safe full of secrets...
I need to know what's in that safe.
In order for this all to work, you need to completely let me in.
Enjoy your evening, gentlemen,
as I consider your proposal.
He knows.
What's going on up there?
Saito knows. He's playing with us.
Doesn't matter. I can get it here. Trust me.
The information is in the safe.
He looked right at it when I mentioned secrets.
What's she doing here?
Just head back to the room. All right? I'll take care of this.
Okay, make sure you do. We're here to work.
If I jumped, would I survive?
With a clean dive, perhaps.
Mal, what are you doing here?
I thought you might be missing me.
You know that I am.
But I can't trust you anymore.
So what?
Looks like Arthur's taste.
Actually, the subject is partial to postwar British painters.
Please, have a seat.
Tell me...
do the children miss me?
You can't imagine.
What are you doing?
Just getting some fresh air.
Stay where you are, Mal.
God, damn it.
Turn around.
The gun, Dom.
Please.
Now the envelope, Mr. Cobb.
Did she tell you? Or have you known all along?
That you're here to steal from me, or that we are actually asleep?
I want to know the name of your employer.
Ah, there's no use threatening him in a dream, right, Mal?
That depends on what you're threatening.
Killing him would just wake him up.
But pain...
Pain is in the mind.
And judging by the decor,
we're in your mind, aren't we, Arthur?
What are you doing? It's too soon.
I know. But the dream's collapsing.
I'm gonna try to keep Saito under a little bit longer.
We're almost there.
He was close. Very close.
Stop him!
This isn't gonna work. Wake him up.
He won't wake.
- Give him the kick. - What?
Dunk him.
He's out.
You came prepared, hmm?
Not even my head of security knows this apartment.
How did you find it?
It's difficult for a man of your position
to keep a love nest like this secret...
particularly where there's a married woman involved.
- She would never... - Yet here we are.
- With a dilemma. - They're getting closer.
- You got what you came for. - Well, that's not true.
You left out a key piece of information, didn't you?
You held something back because you knew what we were up to.
- Question is, why'd you let us in at all? - An audition.
- An audition for what? - Doesn't matter. You failed.
We extracted every bit of information you had in there.
But your deception was obvious.
So leave me and go.
You don't seem to understand, Mr. Saito.
That corporation that hired us, they won't accept failure.
We won't last two days.
Cobb?
Looks like I'm gonna have to do this a little more simply.
Tell us what you know!
Tell us what you know, now!
I've always hated this carpet.
It's stained and frayed in such distinctive ways.
But very definitely made of wool.
Right now...
I'm lying on polyester.
Which means I'm not lying on my carpet, in my apartment.
You have lived up to your reputation, Mr. Cobb.
I'm still dreaming.
- How'd it go? - Not good.
Dream within a dream, huh? I'm impressed.
But in my dream, you play by my rules.
Ah, yes, but you see, Mr. Saito...
We're not in your dream.
We're in mine.
Asshole. How do you mess up the carpet?
- It wasn't my fault. - You're the architect.
I didn't know he was gonna rub his cheek on it!
That's enough.
You. What the hell was all that?
- I have it under control. - I'd hate to see you out of control.
We don't have time for this. I'm getting off at Kyoto.
Why? He's not gonna check every compartment.
Yeah, well, I don't like trains.
Listen. Every man for himself.
Yes, hello?
- Hi, Daddy. - Hi, Dad.
Hey, guys. Hey. How are you? How you doing, huh?
- Good. - Okay, I guess.
Okay? Who's just okay? Is that you, James?
Yeah. When are you coming home, Dad?
Well, I can't, sweetheart. I can't.
Not for a while, remember?
Why?
Look, I told you, I'm away because I'm working, right?
Grandma says you're never coming back.
Phillipa, is that you?
Put Grandma on the phone for me, will you?
She's shaking her head.
Well, just hope she's wrong about that.
Daddy?
Yeah, James?
Is Mommy with you?
James, we talked about this.
Mommy's not here anymore.
Where?
That's enough, kids. Say bye-bye.
Listen, I'm gonna send some presents with Grandpa, all right?
And you be good, you be...
- Our ride's on the roof. - Right.
Hey, are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
Well, down in the dream, Mal showing up.
Look, I'm, uh, sorry about your leg.
Won't happen again.
It's getting worse, isn't it?
One apology's all you're getting, all right, Arthur?
- Where's Nash? - He hasn't shown. You wanna wait?
We were supposed to deliver Saito's expansion plans...
to Cobol Engineering two hours ago
By now, they know we failed.
It's time we disappear.
- Where you gonna go? - Buenos Aires.
I can lie low there,
maybe sniff out a job when things quiet down. You?
Stateside.
Send my regards.
He sold you out. Thought to come to me and bargain for his life.
So I offer you the satisfaction.
It's not the way I deal with things.
- What will you do with him? - Nothing.
But I can't speak for Cobol Engineering.
- What do you want from us? - Inception.
- Is it possible? - Of course not.
If you can steal an idea from someone's mind...
why can't you plant one there instead?
Okay, here's me planting an idea in your head.
I say, "Don't think about elephants".
What are you thinking about?
Elephants.
Right. But it's not your idea,
because you know I gave it to you.
The subject's mind can always trace the genesis of the idea.
- True inspiration's impossible to fake. - That's not true.
- Can you do it? - Are you offering me a choice?
Because I can find my own way to square things with Cobol.
Then you do have a choice.
Then I choose to leave, sir.
Tell the crew where you want to go.
Hey, Mr. Cobb.
How would you like to go home,to America, to your children?
You can't fix that. No one can.
- Just like inception. - Cobb, come on.
- How complex is the idea? - Simple enough.
No idea is simple when you need to plant it
in somebody else's mind.
My main competitor is an old man in poor health.
His son will soon inherit control of the corporation.
I need him to decide to break up his father's empire.
- Cobb, we should walk away from this. - Hold on.
If I were to do this, if I even could do it...
I'd need a guarantee.
- How do I know you can deliver? - You don't.
But I can.
So do you want to take a leap of faith...
or become an old man, filled with regret...
waiting to die alone?
Assemble your team, Mr. Cobb.
And choose your people more wisely.
Look, I know how much you wanna go home.
This can't be done.
Yes, it can.
Just have to go deep enough.
You don't know that.
I've done it before.
Who'd you do it to?
Why are we going to Paris?
We're gonna need a new architect.
You never did like your office, did you?
No space to think in that broom cupboard.
Is it safe for you to be here?
Extradition between France and the United States...
is a bureaucratic nightmare, you know that.
I think they might find a way
to make it work in your case.
Look, I, uh, brought these for you to...
give to the kids when you have a chance.
It'll take more than the occasional stuffed animal...
to convince those children they still have a father.
I'm just doing what I know.
I'm doing what you taught me.
I never taught you to be a thief.
No, you taught me to navigate people's minds.
But after what happened...
there weren't a whole lot of legitimate ways
for me to use that skill.
What are you doing here, Dom?
I think I found a way home.
It's a job for some very, very powerful people.
People who I believe can fix my charges permanently.
But I need your help.
You're here to corrupt one of my brightest and best.
You know what I'm offering.
Let them decide for themselves.
- Money. - Not just money.
You remember.
It's the chance to
build cathedrals, entire cities...
things that never existed...
things that couldn't exist in the real world.
So you want me to let someone else
follow you into your fantasy?
They don't actually come into the dream.
They just design the levels
and teach them to the dreamers. That's all.
Design it yourself.
Mal won't let me.
Come back to reality, Dom.
- Please. - Reality.
Those kids, your grandchildren...
they're waiting for their father to come back home.
That's their reality.
And this job, this last job,
that's how I get there.
I would not be standing here if I knew any other way.
I need an architect who's as good as I was.
I've got somebody better.
Ariadne?
I'd like you to meet Mr. Cobb.
Pleased to meet you.
If you have a few moments,
Mr. Cobb has a job offer.
He'd like to discuss with you.
A work placement?
Not exactly.
I have a test for you.
You're not gonna tell me anything first?
Before I describe the job, I have to know you can do it.
- Why? - It's not, strictly speaking, legal.
You have two minutes to design a maze
that it takes one minute to solve.
Stop.
Again.
You're gonna have to do better than that.
That's more like it.
They say we only use a fraction of our brain's true potential.
Now, that's when we're awake.
When we're asleep, our mind can do almost anything.
Such as?
Imagine you're designing a building.
You consciously create each aspect.
But sometimes, it feels like it's almost creating itself,
if you know what I mean.
Yeah, like I'm discovering it.
Genuine inspiration, right?
Now, in a dream, our mind continuously does this.
We create and perceive our world simultaneously.
And our mind does this so well
that we don't even know it's happening.
That allows us to get right in the middle of that process.
- How? - By taking over the creating part.
Now, this is where I need you.
You create the world of the dream.
We bring the subject into that dream,
and they fill it with their subconscious.
How could I ever acquire enough detail
to make them think that it's reality?
Well, dreams, they feel real while we're in them, right?
It's only when we wake up
that we realize something was actually strange.
Let me ask you a question.
You never really remember the beginning of a dream, do you?
You always wind up right in the middle of what's going on.
I guess, yeah.
So how did we end up here?
Well, we just came from the, uh...
Think about it, Ariadne. How did you get here?
Where are you right now?
We're dreaming?
You're in the middle of the workshop, sleeping.
This is your first lesson in shared dreaming. Stay calm.
If it's just a dream, then why are you covering...
Because it's never just a dream, is it?
And a face full of glass hurts like hell.
When you're in it, it feels real.
That's why the military developed dream sharing.
It was a training program for soldiers to shoot,
stab and strangle each other...
and then wake up.
How did architects become involved?
Well, someone had to design the dreams, right?
Why don't you give us another five minutes?
Five minutes?
What? We were talking for, like, at least an hour.
In a dream, your mind functions more quickly...
therefore time seems to feel more slow.
Five minutes in the real world gives you an hour in the dream.
Why don't you see what you can get up to in five minutes?
You've got the basic layout. Bookstore, cafe?
Almost everything else is here too.
- Who are the people? - Projections of my subconscious.
- Yours? - Yes.
Remember, you are the dreamer. You build this world.
I am the subject. My mind populates it.
You can literally talk to my subconscious.
That's one of the ways we extract information from the subject.
How else do you do it?
By creating something secure,
like a bank vault or a jail.
The mind automatically fills it with information it's trying to protect.
You understand?
- Then you break in and steal it? - Well...
I guess I thought that the dream's space should be all about the visual,
but it's more about the feel of it.
My question is what happens when you
start messing with the physics of it all?
- It's something, isn't it? - Yes, it is.
Why are they all looking at me?
Because my subconscious feels that someone else is creating this world.
The more you change things,
the quicker the projections start to converge on you.
Converge?
They sensed the foreign nature of the dreamer.
They attack like white blood cells fighting an infection.
Are they gonna attack us?
No, actually, just you.
This is great. But I'm telling you,
if you keep changing things like this...
Gees! Mind telling your subconscious to take it easy?
It's my subconscious, remember, I can't control it.
Very impressive.
I know this bridge. This place is real, isn't it?
Yeah, I cross it everyday to get to the college.
Never recreate places from your memory,
always imagine new places.
Well, you gotta draft from stuff you know, right?
Only use details, uh...
A street lamp, or a phone booth, never entire areas.
Why not?
Because building a dream from your memory...
is the easiest way to lose your grasp on  what's real and what is a dream.
- Is that what happened to you? - Listen to me,
this has nothing to do with me, understand?
Is that why you need me to build your dreams?
Get off of her. Back off.
- Back off! - No!
Get off of her!
Mal!
Wake me up! Wake me up!
Mal! Mal!
Hey, hey, hey! Look at me. You're okey? You're okey?
Why... why wouldn't I wake up?
Because there was still some time on the clock,
and you can't wake up within a dream unless you die.
- She'll need a totem. - What?
A totem is a small personal...
That's some subconscious you've got in you, Cobb.
She's a real charmer!
Oh, I see you met Mrs. Cobb.
- She's his wife? - Yeah. So... a totem,
you need a small object potentially heavy,
something could have on you all the time
- that no one else knows. - Like a coin?
No, it must be more unique than that.
This is a loaded die.
No, I can't let you touch it, that would defeat the purpose.
Only I know the balance and the weight of this particular loaded die.
That way, when you look at your totem,
you know, beyond a doubt, that you're not in someone else's dream.
I... I don't know...
if you can't see what's going on, or if you just don't want to,
but Cobb has some serious problems that he's tried to bury down there.
And I'm not about to just open my mind to someone like that.
She'll be back.
I've never seen anyone pick it up that quickly before.
Reality is not gonna be enough for her now.
When she comes back...
when she comes back, you're gonna help her building mazes.
- Where're you gonna be? - I gotta go visit Eames.
Eames? Now he's in Mombasa.
It's Cobol's backyard.
It's a necessary risk.
There's plenty of good thieves.
We don't just need a thief. We need a forger.
You can rub them together all you want, they're not gonna breed.
You never know.
I'll get you a drink.
You're buying.
- Your spelling hasn't improved. - Piss off.
- How's your handwriting? - Versatile.
- Good. - Thank you very much.
Inception.
Now, before you bother telling me it's impossible...
No, it's perfectly possible. It's just bloody difficult.
Just difficult?
Arthur keeps telling me it can't be done.
Hmm... Arthur. You're still working with that stick-in-the-mud?
He's good at what he does, right?
Oh, the best. He has no imagination.
- Not like you. - Listen, if you wanna perform inception,
- you need imagination. - Let me ask you something,
- have you done it before? - We tried it.
We got the idea in place, but it didn't take.
You didn't plant it deep enough?
It's not just about depth, you know...
you need the simplest version of the idea,
in order it to grow naturally in the subject's mind.
That's a very subtle art.
So what is this idea that you need to plant?
We need the heir of a major corporation
to dissolve his father's empire.
Well, you see right there, you have various political motivations of...
anti-monopolistic sentiments and so forth, and all of that stuff.
That's all.
It's really at the mercy of your subject's prejudice, you see?
All you have to do is to start with the absolute basic.
- Which is what? - The relationship with the father.
- Do you have a chemist? - No, not yet.
Alright.
Okey, there's a man here, Yusuf Pierro.
He formulates his own versions of the compounds.
When are you taking me there?
Once you've lost your tail.
Man at the bar.
Cobol engineering.
That price on my head, was that "dead or alive?"
I don't remember. Let's see if he starts shooting.
Run interference, I'll meet you downstairs in the bar in, say uh...
say half an hour?
- Be back here? - It's the last place they'd expect.
Hum-hmm. Well...
Freddy, Freddy Savens?
My God, it's you, isn't it?
No, it isn't.
You're not dreaming now, are you?
There!
Okey.
Oh, uh... cafe. One... one cafe.
One cafe.
Care for a lift, Mr. Cobb?
What're you doing here in Mombasa?
I need to protect my investments.
Ahh, so this is your idea of losing a tail, uh?
Different tail.
Cobb said you'd be back.
I tried not to come. But...
But there's nothing quite like it.
It's just... pure creation.
Shall we take a look at some paradoxical architecture?
You're gonna have to master a few tricks,
if you're gonna build three complete dream levels.
Excuse me.
What kind of tricks?
In a dream, you can cheat architecture into impossible shapes.
That lets you create closed loops,
like the Penrose steps, the infinite staircases.
See?
Paradox.
So a closed loop like that will help you
disguise the boundaries of the dream you create.
But how big do these levels have to be?
It could be anything from the floor of a building to an entire city.
But they have to be complicated
enough that we can hide from the projections.
A maze?
Right, a maze, and the better the maze...
Then the longer we have before the projections catch us?
- Exactly. - My subconscious seems polite enough.
You wait, they'll turn ugly.
No one likes to feel someone else messing around in their mind.
Cobb can't build anymore, can he?
I don't know if he can't, but he won't.
He thinks it's safer if he doesn't know the layouts.
Why?
He won't tell me. I think it's Mal.
- His ex-wife? - No, not his ex.
- They're still together? - No, she...
she's dead.
What you just see in there is just his projection of her.
- What was she like in real life? - She was lovely.
- You're seeking a chemist? - Yes.
To formulate compounds for a job.
And to go into the field with us.
No, I rarely go into the field, Mr. Cobb.
We need you there to tailor compounds specific to our needs.
- Which are? - Great depth.
A dream within a dream? two levels?
- Three. - Not possible.
That many dreams within dreams is too unstable.
It is possible. You just have to add a sedative.
A powerful sedative.
- How many team members? - Five.
Six.
The only way to know you've done the job
is if I go in with you.
There's no room for tourists on a job like this,
Mr. Saito.
This time it seems there is.
This, I think, is a good place to start. I use it everyday.
- What for? - Here, I'll show you.
- Perhaps, you will not want to see. - After you.
Ten... twelve, all connected.
Bloody hell!
They come here everyday to share the dream.
You see? Very stable.
- How long do they dream for? - Three, four hours, each day.
- And the dream time? - With this compound?
About 40 hours, each and every day.
Why do they do it?
Tell him, Mr. Cobb.
After a while,
it becomes the only way you can dream.
Do you still dream, Mr. Cobb?
They come here everyday to sleep?
No, they come to be woken up.
The dream has become their reality. Who are you to say otherwise, uh?
Let's see what you can do.
You know how to find me. You know what you have to do.
Sharp? No?
Are you all right, Mr. Cobb?
Yeah, yeah. I'm just fine.
Robert Fischer,
heir to the Fischer-Morrow Energy Conglomerate.
What's your problem with this Mr. Fischer?
That's not your concern.
Mr. Saito, this...
this isn't your typical corporate espionage.
You asked me for inception, I do hope you understand that...
the gravity of that request.
The seed that we plant in this man's mind will grow into an idea.
This idea would define him. It may come to change...
it may come to change everything about him.
We're the last company standing between them and total energy dominance.
We can no longer compete.
Soon they'll control the energy supply of half the world.
In effect, they become a new superpower.
The world needs Robert Fischer
to change his mind.
That's where we come in.
How is Robert Fischer's
relationship with his father?
Rumor is their relationship is quite complicated.
But we can't work based solely on rumor, can we?
Can you get me access to this man here,
Browning?
Fischer senior's right-hand man,
Fischer junior's godfather.
It should be possible, if you can get the right references.
References are something of a speciality for me, Mr. Saito.
I'm not smelling settlement here.
- Take them down. - Mr. Browning,
Maurice Fischer's policy is always one of
avoiding litigation.
Well, shall we voice your concerns
with Maurice directly?
Not sure if that's necessary.
No, no, no. I think we should.
How is he?
I don't wanna bother him unnecessarily, but...
Robert, I've told you to
keep out the damn...
Just do it!
No, don't speak, Mr. Fischer.
Never... never do thing what I asked.
Leave town.
Must be a cherished memory of this.
I put it beside his bed. He hasn't even noticed it.
Robert, we need to talk about the power of attorney.
I know this is hard for you...
Not now, uncle Peter.
But it's imperative that we start to...
The vultures are circling.
It is the sicker Maurice Fischer becomes,
The more powerful Peter Browning becomes.
I've had ample opportunity to observe Browning,
adopt his physical presence, study his mannerisms, so on and so forth.
So now, in the first layer of the dream,
I can impersonate Browning,
and suggest the concept to Fischer's conscious mind.
Then, when we take him a level deeper,
his own projection of Browning should...
should feed that right back to him.
- So he gives himself the idea? - Precisely.
That's the only way it will stick. It has to seem self-generated.
Eames, I am impressed.
Your condescension, as always,
is much appreciated, Arthur. Thank you.
Were you going under on your own?
No, no. I was just, uh...  just running some experiments.
I didn't realize anyone was here. So...
Yeah, I was just... I was working on my totem, actually.
Here, let me take a look.
So you're learning, huh?
An elegant solution for keeping track of reality.
- Was it your idea? - No, it was, uh...
It was Mal's, actually. This is...
This one was hers.
She'd spin it in a dream and it would never topple,
just spin and spin.
Arthur told me she passed away.
How are the mazes coming along?
Each level relates to the part of the subject's
subconscious that we're trying to access, so...
Making the bottom level hospital,
so Fischer will bring his father, um...
You know, actually I have a question about this layout...
No, no, no. Don't... don't show me the specifics.
Only the dreamer should know the layout.
Why's that so important?
In case one of us brings in our projections,
we don't want them knowing the details of the maze.
You mean in case you bring Mal in?
You can't keep her out, can you?
- Right. - You can't build them because...
if you know the maze, then she knows it.
She'd sabotage the whole operation.
Cobb, did the others know?
No, they don't.
You gotta warn them if this is getting worse.
No one said it's getting worse!
I need to get home.
That's all I care about right now.
Why can't you go home?
Because they think I killed her.
- Thank you. - For what?
For not asking whether I did.
"I will split up my father's empire."
Now this is obviously
an idea that Robert himself would choose to reject.
Just why we need to plant it
deep in his subconscious.
Subconscious is motivated by emotion, right? Not reason.
We need to find a way to translate this into an emotional concept.
How do you translate a business strategy into an emotion?
That's what we have to figure out, right?
Now, Robert's relationship with his father is stressed,
to say the least.
Can we run with that,
we could suggest to him breaking up his
father's company as a "screw you" to the old man?
No,
'cause I think positive emotion trumps negative emotion every time.
We all yearn for reconciliation, a catharsis.
We need Robert Fischer
to have a positive emotional reaction to all this.
Alright, well, try this, um...
"my father accepts that I want to create for myself,
not follow in his footsteps."
- That might work. - Might?
We need to do a little better than "might".
Oh, thank you for your contribution, Arthur.
Forgive me for wanting a little specificities. Specificity?
Inception is not about being specific. When we get inside his mind,
we're gonna have to work with what we find.
On the top level, we open up his relationship with his father,
say, "I will not follow in my father's footsteps."
Then the next level down, we feed him,
"I will create something for myself."
Then, by the time we hit the bottom level, we bring out the big guns...
- "my father doesn't want me to be him. - Exactly.
With three layers down, the dreams are gonna collapse...
with the slightest disturbance.
Sedation, for a sleep...
stable enough to create three layers of dreaming.
We have to combine with an extremely powerful sedative.
Good night.
The compound we'll be using to share the dream
creates very clear connection between dreamers,
whilst actually accelerating brain function.
In other words, it gives us more time on each level.
Brain function in the dream will be about twenty times normal.
When you enter a dream within that dream, the effect is compounded.
Three dreams, that's ten hour times twenty...
I'm sorry, uh...
math's never my strong subject.
- How much time is that? - It's a week the first level down.
Six months the second level down. And the third level...
Ten years.
Who would wanna be stuck in a dream for ten years?
Depends on the dream.
So once we've made the plant, how do we get out?
I'm hoping you have something more
elegant in mind than shooting me in the head?
- A kick.- What's a kick?
This, Ariadne, would be a kick.
It's that feeling of falling, you get the jolts to wake.
It snaps you out of the dream.
Are we gonna feel a kick with this kind of sedation?
Oh, that's the clever part.
I customize the sedative
to leave inner ear function unimpaired.
That way, however deep the sleep, the sleeper still feels falling,
or tipping.
The trick is to synchronize a kick that can penetrate all three levels.
We can use a musical countdown
to synchronize different kicks.
He hasn't any surgery schedule, no dental, nothing.
Wasn't he supposed to have a knee operation?
Nothing. Nothing they'd put him under for, anyway. We need...
We need at least a good ten hours.
Sydney to Los Angeles,
One of the longest flights in the world.
He makes it every two weeks.
And he must be flying private.
Not if there were unexpected maintenance with his plane.
- It'd have to be a 747.- Why is that?
Cause on a 747, pilots are up top,
And the first class cabin's in the nose,
So no one would walk through.
But you'd have to buyout the entire cabin,
And the first class flight attendant.
I bought the airline.
It seemed neater.
It looks like we have our ten hours.
Ariadne? Terrific work, by the way.
You know how to find me.
You know what you have to do.
You remember when you asked me to marry you?
- Of course I do.- You said you had a dream.
- That we grow old together.- And we can.
You shouldn't be in here.
I just want to see what kind of
"tests" you're doing on your own every night.
Whatever it was, it has nothing to do with you.
It has everything to do with me.
- You've asked me to share dreams with you.- Not these.
These are my dreams.
Why do you do this to yourself?
This is the only way I can still dream.
Why is it so important to dream?
In my dreams we're still together.
These aren't just dreams. These are memories.
- And you said never to use memories.- I know I did.
You're trying to keep her alive.you can't let her go.
You don't understand.
These are moments I regret,
the memories that I have to change.
Well, what's down there that you regret?
Listen, there's only one thing you need to understand about me.
- This is your house? - Mine and Mal's, yes.
- Where is she?  - She's already gone.
It's my son, James.
He's digging for something, maybe a worm.
That's Philippa.
You see, I thought about calling out to them,
so they'd turn and smile and I can see those...
Those beautiful faces of theirs.but... It's all too late.
Right now, or never, Cobb.
Then I start to panic.
I realize I don't wanna regret this moment, that I..
I need to see their faces one last time.
James! Philippa! Come on in!
But the moment's passed.
Whatever I do I can't change this moment.
When I'm about to call out to them, they run away.
If I'm ever gonna see their faces again, I've gotta get back home,
In the real world.
- What are you doing here?  - My name is...
I know who you are.  What are you doing here?
- I'm just trying to understand.- How could you understand?
Do you know what it is to be a lover?
- To be half of a whole?  - No.
I'll tell you a riddle.
You're waiting for a train, a train that will take you far away.
You know where you hope this train will take you,
But you don't know for sure.
But it doesn't matter.
How can it not matter to you where that train will take you?
Because you'll be together.
How could you bring her here, Dom?
What is this place?
This is a hotel suite where we spent our anniversary.
What happened here?
You promised! you promised we'd be together!
Please, I need you stay here, just for now.
You said we'd be together! you said we'd grow old together!
I'll come back for you, I promise.
Do you think you can just build a prison of memories to lock her in?
Do you really think that's gonna contain her?
It's time.Maurice Fischer just died in Sydney.
- When's the funeral? - Thursday, in Los Angeles.
Robert should accompany the body no later than Tuesday.
We should move.
- Right. - Cobb, I'm coming with you.
I promised Miles. No.
The team needs someone who understands what you're struggling with.
And it doesn't have to be me,
but then you have to show Arthur what I just saw.
Get us another seat on the plane.
If I get on this plane, and you don't honor our agreement,
When we land, I go to jail for the rest of my life.
Complete the job en route, I make one phone call from the plane,
You'll have no trouble getting through immigration.
- I'm sorry. - Oh, yeah. I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Excuse me, I think this is yours?  You must've dropped it.
- Would you gentlemen care for a drink?  - Oh, water, please.
Same, please.
Umm... thank you.
You know, I couldn't help but notice, but...
You wouldn't happen to be related to "the Maurice Fischer", will you?
Yes, he, um... he was my father.
He was a very inspiring figure. I'm sorry for your loss.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
Hey, to your father. May he rest in peace.
- Couldn't you have peed before you went under. - Sorry.
Bit too much free champagne before takeoff, Yusuf?
Aha, bloody ha.
Well now, he's gonna be looking for a taxi in this weather.
- Asshole! Hey man, why don't you try... - Walk away.
I gotta go. Taxi! Thank you.
Alright...Snappy!
- What're you doing?  - I'm sorry. I thought it was free.
- No, it's not. - Maybe we could share.
Maybe not. Can you pull over to get this...
Great.
Come on.
There's five hundred dollars in there,
And the wallet's worth more than that.
- So you might at least drop me at my stop.  - I'm afraid...
- Covering him!  - No! no! no!
What was going on?
This wasn't in the design.
Cobb. Cobb?
Get him!
- Are you alright? - Yeah, I'm alright, I'm okey. I'm okey.
- Fischer's okey. Unless he gets carsick. - Saito?
Get Fischer in the back room, now.
- Get him in the back room. Move! - What the hell?
- Has he been shot? Is he dying? - I don't know.
Jesus Christ!
Where were you? what happened to you?
We were blocked by a freight train.
Why would you put a train crossing in
The middle of a downtown intersection?
- I didn't.- Where did it come from?
Lemme ask you a question! Why the hell we were ambushed, huh?
Those were not normal projections.
He'd been trained, for god's sakes!
- You're right.- How could he be trained?
Fischer's had an extractor teach his subconscious
to defend itself. so...
His subconscious is militarized. This should have shown in the research.
- I'm sorry.- Why the hell you didn't?
- Calm down. - Don't tell me to calm down!
This was your job, goddamnit! This was your responsibility!
You were meant to check Fischer's background thoroughly!
We are not prepared for this type of fire!
We have dealt with the subsecurity before.
We'll be a little more careful.we're gonna be fine.
"Before" is not a part of the plan! He's dying, for god's sake!
- Let's put him out of his misery. - Don't do that! Don't do that!
He's in agony. I'm waking him up.
No, it won't wake him up.
- What do you mean, it won't wake him up? - It won't wake him up.
When we die in a dream, we wake up.
Not from this.
We're too heavily sedated to wake up that way.
Right. so what happens when we die?
- Drop into limbo. - Are you serious?
- Limbo?  - Unconstructed dream space.
What the hell is down there?
Just raw infinite subconscious.
Nothing is down there,
except for whatever might have been left behind
by anyone sharing the dream who's been trapped there before,
Which in our case is just you.
But how long could we be stuck there?
Not even think about trying to escape until the sedation eases...
How long?
Decades, it could be infinite, I don't know.
Ask him. he's the one who's been there.
Let's just get him upstairs.
Great. Thank you.
So, now we are trapped in Fischer's mind
battling his own private army.
And if we get killed,
we'll be lost in limbo
till our brains turn to scrambled egg. hmm?
You got first aid?
So you knew about these risks. You didn't tell us?
There wasn't meant to be any risk.
I didn't know we'd be dealing with a load of gunfire.
You had no right.
This is the only way to go three layers deep.
And you, you knew about this and went along with it?
I trusted him.
You trusted him? When? When he promised you half his share?
No, his whole share.
Besides, he said he had done it before.
You had done it before? What? With Mal?
- Cause that works so good? - That has nothing to do with it.
I did what I had to do to get back to my children.
So you led us into a war zone with no way out?
There's a way out, alright?
We continue on with the job, and we do this as fast as possible,
And we get out using the kick, just like before.
Forget it. If we go any deeper, we just raise the stakes.
I am sitting this one hour on this level, worse?
Fischer's security is surrounding this place
Fischer's security is surrounding this place as we speak.
The ten hours of flight time is a week at this level.
That means each and every one of us will be killed, that I can guarantee.
We have no other choice but to continue on and do it as fast as possible.
Downwards, is the only way forwards.
Get ready. You, come on.
Let's go shake him up.
I'm insured against kidnaping for up to ten million.
This should be very simple.
Shut up! It won't be.
In your father's office, below the bookshelves, is his personal safe.
- We need the combination. - I don't know any safe.
It doesn't mean you don't know the combination. Tell us what it is.
I don't know.
We have it on good authority you do know.
Yeah? Who's this authority?
- Five hundred dollars this cost. - Open inside.
Cash, cards, ID, and this.
- Useful? - Maybe.
- You're on. you've got an hour. - An hour?
I was supposed to have all night to crack this.
Saito wasn't supposed to be shot in the chest.
Got one hour to get something useful, please.
What's that?
Good authority.
Uncle Peter.
- Just... just make them stop. - The combination?
- I don't know it.- What does Browning say you do.
I don't know. Just lemme... lemme talk to him,
and I'll find out.
You have one hour. Start talking.
Are you okey?
Those bastards've had me for two days.
They have someone with access to your father's office.
- And they're trying to open his safe.- Yeah.
They thought I'd know the combination, but I don't know it.
- Yeah, well, neither do I. so... - What?
Maurice told me that when he passed,
you are the only one to be able to open it.
No, he never... he never gave me any combination.
Maybe he did, I mean,
maybe you just didn't know it was a combination.
- Well, what then? - I don't know.
Some meaningful combination of numbers based on your...
your experiences with Maurice.
We didn't have very many, um... meaningful experiences together.
Perhaps, after your mother died.
After my mother died, you know what he told me?
"Robert, there's really nothing to be said."
Oh, he was bad with emotions.
I was eleven, uncle peter.
- How's he doing? - He's in a lot of pain.
When we get down to the lower levels, the pain will be less intense.
- And if he dies? - The worst case scenario?
When he wakes up, his mind is completely gone.
Cobb, I'll still honor the arrangement.
I appreciate that, Saito. But..
When you wake up, you won't even remember that we had an arrangement.
Limbo's gonna become your reality.
You're gonna be lost down there so
long that you're gonna become an old man.
- Filled with regret. - Waiting to die alone?
No, I'll come back. and we'll be young men, together again.
Breathe.
These people are gonna kill us here,
if we don't give them the combination.
- They just want a ransom. - I heard them.
They're gonna whack us in that van and then drive it into the river.
Alright, what is it in the safe?
Something for you.
Maurice always said it was his most precious gift to you.
- A will.  - Maurice's will is with Port and Dunn.
That's an alternate.
This would supersede the other, if you want it to.
It splits up the component businesses of Fischer-Morrow,
and it'd be the end of the entire empire as we know it.
Destroy my whole inheritance?
- Why would he suggest such a thing? - I just don't know.
He loved you, Robert, in his own way.
In his own way?
At the end, he called me to his deathbed.
He could barely speak.
But he took the trouble to tell me one last thing.
He pulled me close.
And I could only make out one word --
"disappointed."
When were you in limbo?
You might have the rest of the team convinced to carry on with this job,
- But they don't know the truth? - Truth? What truth?
The truth that at any minute,
you might bring a freight train through the wall.
The truth that Mal is bursting through your subconscious.
And the truth that as we go deeper into Fischer,
We're also going deeper into you.
And I'm not sure we're gonna like what we find.
We were working together.
We were exploring the concept of a dream within a dream.
I kept pushing things. I wanted to go deeper and deeper.
I wanted to go further.
I just didn't understand the concept
that hours could turn into years down there,
And we could get trapped so deep that only
wound up on the shore of our own subconscious.
We lost sight of what was real.
We created and built a world for ourselves.
We did that for years.
We built our own world.
- How long were you stuck there? - Something like fifty years.
Jeez. How could you stand it?
It wasn't so bad at first, feeling like gods.
The problem was none of them was real.
Eventually, it just became impossible for me to live like that.
And what about for her?
She had locked something away, something deep inside her.
The truth that she had once known,
but she chose to forget.
Limbo became her reality.
What happened when you woke up?
Well, to wake up from that after... after years, after decades,
We come old souls thrown back into youth like that.
I knew something was wrong with her.
she just wouldn't admit it.
Eventually, she told me the truth.
She was possessed by an idea.
This one very simple idea that changed everything,
That our world wasn't real,
That she needed to wake up to come back to reality, that...
In order to get back home, we had to kill ourselves.
What about your children?
she thought they were projections,
That our real children were waiting for us up there somewhere.
- I am their mother. - Calm down.
Don't you think I can't tell the difference?
If this is my dream, why can't I control this?
Because you don't know you're dreaming!
She was certain there was nothing I can do,
No matter how much I begged, no matter how much I pleaded.
She wanted to do it, but she could not do it alone.
She loved me too much, so...
She came up with the plan on our anniversary.
- Sweetheart, what are you doing? - Join me.
Just... just step back inside. Alright?
Just step back inside. now, come on.
No.
I'm going to jump. And you are coming with me.
No, I'm not.
Now... now you listen to me.
If you jump, you're not gonna wake up. Remember?
You're gonna die. now just... just step back inside.
Come on!
Step back inside so we can talk about this.
we've talked enough.
Mal.
Come out onto the ledge, or I'll jump right now.
Okey.
Let's talk about this. Alright?
- I'm asking you to take a leap of faith. - No, honey,
I can't. you know I can't do that.
Take a second to think about our children.
Think about James, think about Phillipa, now.
If I go without you, they'll take them away, anyway.
- What does that mean? - I filed a letter with our attorney,
explaining how I'm fearful for my safety,
How you threatened to kill me.
- why did you do this? - I love you, Dom.
Why did you... why... why would you do this to me?
Freed you from the guilt of choosing to leave them.
We are going home, to our real children.
No, no... no. Mal, you listen to me, alright?
Mal, look at me, please!
you're waiting for a train,
Mal, goddamnit! Don't do this!
a train that will take you far away.
James and Phillipa are waiting for you!
You know where you hope this train will take you,
- They're waiting for us! - But you don't know for sure.
- Mal, look at me! - But it doesn't matter,
- Mal, goddamnit! - Because we'll be together.
Sweetheart! Look at me!
Mal! No! Jesus Christ!
She had herself declared sane by three different psychiatrists,
That made it impossible for me to
Try to explain the nature of her madness.
So they're in.
Right now, or never, Cobb.
Fine, let's go.
I left my children behind,
And I've been trying to buy my way back ever since.
Your guilt defines her, it's what powers her.
But you are not responsible for the idea that destroyed her.
And if we're gonna succeed in this,
you have to forgive yourself,
And you're gonna have to confront her.
But you don't have to do that alone.
No, you don't...
I'm doing it for the others.
Because they have no idea of the risk
they've taken coming down here with you.
We have to move.
- Time's up. - All right.
I don't know any combination, not consciously anyway.
How about instinctively, huh?
I've got somebody standing in your father's office.
Right now, we need to tap in the combination.
We need the first six numbers that come to your head right now.
- I have no idea. - Right now!
I said right now! Right now!
You'd have to do better than that.
Alright, bag them.
We're going for a ride.
We're worth much more to you alive...
You hear me?
What did you get?
That boy's relationship with his father is even worse than we imagined.
This helps us how?
The stronger the issues, the more powerfully cathartic.
How are you gonna reconcile them of so estranged?
- Well, I'm working on that, an't I? - Move fast.
The projections are closing in quick.
we gotta break out of here,
Before we're totally boxed in.
Damn it!
You mustn't be afraid to dream a little bigger, darling.
Now, we need to shift his animosity
from his father to his godfather.
Would this destroy his one positive relationship?
No,
We'll repair his relationship with his
father by exposing his godfather's true nature.
Hell, we should charge Fischer much more than Saito.
What about his security?
It's gonna get worse as we go deeper.
Now, I think we run with Mr. Charles.
No.
- Who's Mr. Charles? - Bad idea.
The second we get into that hotel and approach fischer,
His security's gonna be all over us.
We run with Mr. Charles
like we did on the Stein Job.
- So you've done it before? - Yeah, it didn't work.
The subject realized that he was dreaming,
And his subconscious tore us to pieces.
Excellent. but you've learnt a lot, right?
- I need some kind of distraction. - No problem.
How about a lovely lady I've used before.
- Listen to me. you drive carefully, alright? - Yeah.
The thing down there's gonna be unstable as hell.
Don't jump too soon.
We only have one shot at that kick you're gonna make.
I'll play the music, then you'll know it's coming.
the rest is on you.
- Are you ready? - Ready!
Sweet dreams!
Am I boring you?
I was telling you my story. I guess it wasn't your liking.
Oh, um... I have a lot in my mind.
There goes Mr. Charles.
Mr. Fischer? Right?
Pleasure to see you again. Rod Green from marketing.
- And you must be...? - Leaving.
In case you get bored...
Must have blown you off.
That is unless her phone number, really is only six digits.
Funny way down, make friends,
someone stealing their wallet like that.
Ha, goddamnit! Wallet alone is worth at least...
About 500 dollars, right?
Listen, don't worry about it. My people are already on it as we speak.
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
It's a gambit designed to turn Fischer against his own subconscious.
Then why don't you approve?
'cause it involves telling the mark that he's dreaming,
Which involves attracting a lot of attention on us.
Didn't cobb say never to do that?
So now you've noticed how much time
Cobb spends doing things he says never to do.
Mr. Saito, can I have a moment?
Oh, I... I'm sorry.
Wait!
- You look a bit perkier. - Very amusing, Mr. Eames.
Turbulence on the plane?
No, it's much closer. It's Yusuf's driving.
- I'm sorry, who did you say you were? - Rod Green from marketing.
That's not true at all, is it?
My name is Mr. Charles. You remember me, don't you?
I'm the head of your security down here.
Get out on a different floor and keep moving.
- Dump the wallet. The security will look for that. - Okey.
We need to buy cobb a little more time.
Security, huh?
- You work for the hotel? - No, no.
I specialize in a very specific type of security,
subconscious security.
Are you talking about dreams?
Are you talking about, um... extraction?
I'm here to protect you.
Mr. Fischer, I'm here to protect you
In the event that someone tries access to your mind through your dreams.
You are not safe here. They are coming for you.
Strange weather, isn't it?
You feel that?
What's happening?
Cobb's drawing Fischer's attention to the strangeness of the dream,
which is making his subconscious look for the dreamer,
For me. Quick, give me a kiss.
- They're still looking at us. - Yeah, it's worth a shot.
We should probably get out of here.
Do you feel that?
You've actually been trained for this, Mr. Fischer.
Pay attention to the strangeness of the weather, the shift of the gravity.
None of this is real. You're in a dream.
Now, the easiest way for you to test yourself is to try to remember,
How you arrived at this hotel. Can you do that?
Year, I don't, I...
Now, breathe, breathe. Remember your training,
Accept the fact that you're in the dream, and I'm here to protect you.
Go on.
- You're not real? - No, no.
I'm a projection of your subconscious.
I was sent here to protect you in the event
that the extractors try to pull you into a dream.
And I believe that's what's going on right now, Mr. Fischer.
Yeah, okey.
Okey.
- Can you get me out of here? - Right away. Follow me.
This is what? What're you doing?
These men were sent here  to abduct you, alright?
If you want my help, you have to remain calm.
I need you to work with me, Mr. Fischer.
If this is a dream, I should just kill myself to wake up. Right?
I wouldn't do that if I were you, mr. fischer.
I believe that they have you sedated.
If... if you pull that trigger, you may not wake up.
You may go into a further dream state now.
You know what I'm talking about.
You remember the training. Remember what I said to you.
Give me the gun.
- This room should be directly below 528? - Yeah.
Think, Mr. Fischer, think.
What do you remember from before this dream?
Oh... there was, um... there was a lot of gunfires.
There was... rain.
Uncle peter.
- Oh my god, we've been kidnaped. - Where were they holding you?
- They had us in the back of a van. - That explains the gravity shifts.
You're in the back of a van right now. Ke...keep going!
It had something to do with, um... something to do with a... a safe.
God, why is it so hard to remember?
It's like trying to remember a dream after you've woken up.
Listen to this, it takes years of practice.
You and Browning have been pulled into this dream,
Because they're trying to steal something from your mind.
I need you to focus and try to remember what that is.
What is it, Mr. Fischer? Think!
Uh... a combination.
They demanded the first numbers that popped into my head.
They were trying to extract the number from your subconscious.
It can represent anything. We are in a hotel right now.
Should try hotel rooms. What was the number, Mr. Fischer?
Try and remember for me. This is very important.
5...52... it was something long number...
That's good enough.
We could start there.
- Fifth floor. - Yep.
- So do you use a timer? - No, I have to judge it for myself.
While you're all asleep in 528.
I wait for Yusuf's kick.
- Well, how will you know? - His music warns me.
And then when the van hits the barrier of the bridge,
That should be unmistakable. So we get a nice, synchronized kick.
If it's too soon, we won't get pulled out.
And if it's too late, I won't be able to drop this.
- Why not? - Because of the van that will be in free fall.
- Can't drop you without gravity. - Right.
They're with me.
- Mr. Charles. - Do you know
what that is, Mr. Fischer?
Yeah, I... I think so. yeah.
They were trying to put you under.
- I'm already under. - Under again.
What do you mean? A... Dream within a dream?
- Hey, I see you've changed. - I'm sorry?
Oh... I'm sorry. I've mistaken you for a friend.
Good looking fella, I'm sure.
That's fischer's projection of browning.
Let's follow him and see how he behaves.
- Why? - Because how he acts would tell us...
If Fischer's starting to suspect his motives as the way we wanted to.
- Uncle peter? - You said you were kidnaped together?
Well, um... well, not... not exactly.
They... they already had him.they were torturing him.
And you saw them torture him?
The kidnapers are working for you?
Oh, Robert...
You're trying to get that safe open? So you get the alternate will?
Fischer-Morrow has been my entire life.
I can't let you destroy it.
I'm not gonna throw away my inheritance! Why would I?
I couldn't let you rise to your father's last taunt.
What taunt?
The will, Robert.
That will, that's his last insult, a challenge for you...
you'd build something for yourself,
by telling you you're not worthy of his accomplishments.
- Well, that he was, um... disappointed. - Hmm, I'm sorry.
But... he's wrong.
You can build a better company than he ever did.
- Mr. Fischer, he's lying. - How do you know?
Trust me, it's what I do.
He's hiding something,
And we need to find out what that is.
I need you to do the same thing to him that he was going to do to you.
We'll enter his subconscious and
find out what he doesn't want you to know.
All right.
He's out.
Wait, whose subconscious are we going into exactly?
We're going into Fischer's.
But I told him it was Browning's,
so he can be a part of our team.
He's gonna help us break into his own subconscious.
That's right.
The security's gonna run you down, huh?
Then I will lead them on a merry chase.
Just be back before the kick.
Go to sleep, Mr. Eames.
Are you good?
- Hey! Are you ready? - Yes, yes, I'm... I'm fine. I'm ready.
Cobb. cobb? What's down there?
Hopefully the truth we want Fischer to learn.
I mean, what's down there for you?
Huh... did you see that?
Eames, this is your dream.
I need you to draw the security away from the complex. Do you understand?
- Who will guide Fischer in? - Not me.
If I know the route, everything could be compromised.
- I... I designed the place. - No, you're with me.
- I can do it. - Alright.
You brief him on the route into the complex.
Fischer, you'll be going with him.
Alright. What about you?
Keep this live. I'll be listening in the whole time.
The windows on that upper floor're big
enough for me to cover you from that south tower.
- You see it? - Yeah. you're not coming in?
In order to find out the truth about your father,
you're gonna need to break into Browning's mind on your own.
Come, Fischer!
Sound the alarm! Sound the alarm!
Move!
Go!
Hope you're ready.
No, it's too soon.
Cobb, do you hear that?
First heard it about twenty minutes ago. I thought it was the wind up here.
Yeah, I hear it. It's music.
- So what do we do? - Move fast!
Yusuf's ten seconds for the jump,
which gives Arthur three minutes.
- Which gives us what? - Sixty minutes.
Can they make that route in under an hour?
They still have to climb down to the middle terrace.
Well, then they need a new route, a more direct route.
There!
It's designed as a labyrinth.
There must be access routes that cut through the maze, right?
Eames.
- Did Eames add any features? - I don't think I should tell you.
- If Mal finds out... - We don't have time for this.
Did he add any?
He added an airduct system that can cut through the maze.
Good, explain it to them.
- Saito? - Go ahead?
- Paradox. - No...!
- What was that? - The kick.
- Cobb! Cobb, did we miss it? - Yeah, we missed it.
Couldn't someone have dreamt up a goddamned beach, huh?
- What the hell do we do now? - We finish the job before the next kick.
- What next kick? - When the van hits the water.
If you want to make a call, please hang up and try again.
How can I drop you without gravity?
Arthur has a couple of minutes, we have about twenty.
Are you okey?
Move on! To the base!
There's something wrong, they're heading your way,
like they know something.
Just buy us some more time, alright? Come on!
On my way.
That's the antechamber outside the strong room.
Does the strong room have windows?
Well, I mean it wouldn't be very strong if it did.
Let's hope Fischer likes what he finds in there.
- Are those projections part of his subconscious? - Yes.
- Are you destroying those parts of his mind? - No, no.
They're just projections.
Okey. We are here.
You are clear but hurry. There's an entire army heading your way.
We're in.
Look here!
- Someone else's in there. - Fischer, it's a trap. Get out!
Come on, a little lower.
Cobb. No, she...
- She is not real. - How do you know that?
She is just a projection. Fischer... Fischer is real.
Hello.
Eames! Eames! Get to the antechamber now!
- What happened? - Mal killed Fischer?
I couldn't shoot her.
There's no use in reviving him, his mind's already trapped down there.
- It's all over. - So that's it? Then we failed?
We're done. I'm sorry.
Well, it's not me who doesn't get back to my family, is it?
It's a shame. I really wanted to know what's gonna happen in there.
I swear we had this one.
Let's set the charges.
No, there's still another way.
- We just have to follow Fischer down there. - Not enough time.
No, but there will... there will be enough time down there.
And we will find him, okey?
As soon as Arthur's music kicks in,
just use the defibrillator to revive him.
We can give him his... his own kick down below.
Look, you get him in there.
As soon as the music ends, you blow up the hospital,
and we all ride the kick back up the layers.
That's worth a shot.
Saito can hold the guards out, while I set the charges.
Saito will never make it, will he?
- Cobb, come on. We've got to try this. - Let's go.
If you are not back for the kick, I will go with or without you.
She's right. She's right. Let's go.
Can I trust you to do what needs to happen here?
I mean, Mal's gonna be down there.
I know where to find her. She'll have Fischer.
- How do you know? - Because...
She wants me to come after her,
she wants me back down there with her.
Are you alright?
- This is your world? - Was. This is where she'll be.
Come on.
Come here.
Saito, Saito!
I need you, I need you to take care of Fischer,
while I go set some charges. Okey?
No room for tourists on this job.
Who said?
You built all this? This is incredible.
We built it for years.
And we started it on the memories.
This way.
This is our neighborhood,
The place is from our past.
That was our first apartment.
And we moved to that building right there, after Mal became pregnant,
that became my home.
You reconstructed all of this from memory?
Like I told you, we had lots of time.
- What's that? - It's the house Mal grew up in.
- Will she be in there? - No.
Come on.
We both wanted to live in that house, but we loved this type of building.
In the real world, we'd have to choose, but not here.
How would you bring Fischer back?
We have to come up with some kind of a kick.
- What? - We'd better improvise.
Listen, there's something you should know about me, about inception.
An idea is like a virus, resilient, highly contagious.
A smallest seed of an idea can grow.
It can grow to define or destroy you.
The smallest idea such as "your world is not real,"
Simple little thought that changes everything.
So certain of your world of what's real.
Do you think he is?
What do you think he is as lost as I was?
I know what's real, Mal.
No creeping doubts,
not feeling persecuted, Dom?
Chased around the globe by anonymous corporations and police forces?
Or whether the projections persecute the dreamer?
Admit it,
you don't believe in one reality anymore.
So choose, choose to be here,
Choose me.
You know why I have the deal, have to get back to our children?
Because you left them,
because you left us.
- You're wrong! - I'm not wrong.
You're confused.
Our children are here.
And you'd like to see their faces again, wouldn't you?
Yes. But I want to see them up above, Mal.
Up above?
Listen to yourself.
These are our children.
Watch.
James! Phillipa!
Don't do this, Mal. Please.
Those aren't my children.
You keep telling yourself that, but you don't believe it.
- No, I know it! - What if you're wrong?
What if I'm what's real?
You keep telling yourself what you know.
But what do you believe?
What do you feel?
Guilt.
I feel guilt, Mal.
No matter what I do, no...
no matter how hopeless I am, no matter how I confused, that guilt...
is always there, reminding me of the truth.
What truth?
That the idea that caused you to question your reality
came from me.
You planted the idea in my mind?
What is she talking about?
The reason I knew inception was possible was because I...
I did it to her first.
- I did it to my own wife. - Why?
We were lost in here.
I knew we needed to escape, but she wouldn't accept it.
She had locked something away, something.... something deep inside.
The truth that she had once known, but she chose to forget.
She couldn't break free.
So I decided to search for it,
going deep into the recess of her mind and found that secret place.
I broke in.
Then I planted an idea,
a simple little idea that would change everything.
That "her world wasn't real."
"the death was the only escape."
You're waiting for a train,
The train that'll take you far away.
You know where you hope this train will take you,
But you can't know for sure.
But it doesn't matter.
Now tell me why!
Because we'll be together!
But I never knew that...
that idea would grow in her mind like a cancer,
that even after she woke up.
That even after you came back to reality.
That you continue to believe your world wasn't real.
That death was the only escape.
Mal! No! Jesus...
- You infected my mind? - I was trying to save you.
You betrayed me.
But you can make amends, you can still keep your promise.
We can still be together,
right here, in the world we built together.
Cobb, we need to get Fischer.
You can't have him.
- If I stay here, would you let them go? - What're you talking about?
Fischer's on the porch.
- Go check if he's alive. - Cobb, you can't do this.
Go check if he's alive, right now. Do it.
Cobb, he's here. And it's time. You have to come now!
Take Fischer with you, alright?
You can't stay here to be with her.
I'm not. Saito's dead by now, that means he's down here somewhere.
It means I have to find him.
I can't stay with her anymore, because she doesn't exist.
I'm the only thing you do believe in anymore.
No. I wish...
I wish more than anything, but...
I can't imagine you with all your complexity,
all your perfection, all your imperfection.
You alright?
Look at you,
you're just a shade.
You're just the shade of my real wife.
You're the best that I could do, but...
I'm sorry, you are just not good enough.
Doesn't this feel real?
- What're you doing? - Improvise.
No, no! No!
Get in there, now. Go! Go, go, go!
Robert?
Dis... disap...
- I was disa... disa... - I know, dad.
I know you were disappointed, I couldn't be you.
No, no, no.
I was disappointed...
That you tried.
What?
That's the kick, Ariadne! You have to go now!
Don't lose yourself! Find Saito and bring him back!
I will!
Do you remember when you asked me to marry you?
Yes.
You said you dreamt that we grow old together.
But we did.
We did, you don't remember?
I miss you more than I can bear, but...
we had our time together.
I have to let you go.
I'm sorry, Robert.
You know, the will means that dad wanted me to be my own man.
Not just to live for him.
That's what I'm gonna do, uncle Peter.
- What happened? - Cobb stayed.
- With Mal? - No, to find Saito.
He'll be lost.
No, he'll be alright.
Have you come to kill me?
I'm waiting for someone,
someone from a half remembered dream.
Cobb?
Impossible.
We were young men together.
I'm an old man.
Filled with regret.
Waiting to die alone, huh?
I've come back for you,
to remind you...
of something...
something you once knew.
That this world is not real.
To convince me to honor our arrangement.
To take a leap of faith, yes.
Come back,
so we can be young men together again.
Come back with me.
Come back.
Hot towel, sir?
We will be landing in Los Angeles in about twenty minutes.
Do you need immigration forms?
Thank you.
- Hot towel, sir? - Oh, no.
Do you need immigration forms?
Welcome home, Mr. Cobb.
Thank you, sir.
Welcome home.
This way.
James? Philippa?
Look who's here.
- Daddy! Daddy! - Hey, kids! How are you?
- Look what I built? - What're you doing there?
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer1705
- I built a house on the cliff. - Out of rocks?
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer